Pierre FABER

Profile

Newly graduated as a computer engineer in France, seeking work experience in Ireland. Passionate about coding for twelve years looking for a job in web development. Hardworking, loving to learn new things and autonomous, proud to have carried out several personal IT projects. I'm ready to join my next team!

Employment History

Web developer at Solutec, Lyon (France)

February 2023 - July 2023

SCRUM method, ScrumMaster, Figma modelling, Gitlab CI/CD, TDD development with Jest. *Languages*: Vue 3, Node.js, Vuetify, Pinia, PostgreSQL, Sequelize/Umzug, TypeScript

Software Development Engineer at Institute for Radiation Protection and Nuclear Safety, Fontenay-aux-Roses (France)

May 2022 - August 2022

Automation of python tests and development of a tool for reading scientific data (weather) in C++.

Junior Tech Leader at Potions & engineering school INSA, Rouen (France)

January 2022 - June 2022

Creation of a decentralized messaging mobile application with Flutter and Gun.js. Intermediate use of the NoSQL database firebase. Application of the scrum method within a student team. Implementation of test pipeline and deployment of the application.

Salesperson in the computer department at retailer Darty, Châtillon (France)

January 2020 - February 2020

Advice and customer relations within the IT department. Creation of Microsoft Office human resources documents (Excel, Word, PowerPoint).

Education

National Institute of Applied Sciences (INSA), Rouen (France) - Engineering Degree

September 2020 - July 2023

Department of Computing and Information Technology - Web Development and Machine Learning Specialization

Details

+337 82 62 38 57 faberpierre78@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn Github Personal Website

Hobbies

Scoutism, Piano, Coding and Sport (Baseball, Basketball, Ping-pong and Volley)

Languages

French - Native

English - B2

TOEIC Score: 855

German - B1

Université Laval, Québec (Canada) - Bachelor Degree

September 2022 – December 2022

Web Development, Cyberattacks, Software Quality and Metrics and Video Game Development

Ecole Française d'Electronique et d'Informatique, Villejuif Associate's Degree

September 2018 - July 2020

Preparatory class for engineering schools. Specialization in IT

■ Personal Projects

Mango - Mobile application for reading manga

Ionic, AngularJS, Node.js, Typescript, SCSS, Web Scraping

Platypus 2 - Code learning website - Vue.js, PostgreSQL

Rummikub Online - Online board game

Node.js (Express, Socket.io), HTML, Javascript, CSS

Bubbles - Social Network - PHP, MySQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS

UFood - Website for sharing restaurant reviews

Vue.js, API Rest, Map Location

TV Replay - TV Replay Application

Python (Flask, Helium), HTML, CSS

BloGame - Video game blog host

Java EE (Wildfly), HTML, CSS, Javascript

Y Extra-curricular activities

Scoutmaster at Scout et Guide de France, Montigny-le-Bretonneux

September 2011 - Present

Boy scout since childhood and now scoutmaster of thirty young people in France. Organize activities all year round and a two-week camp in the summer with my team of scoutmasters.

Volunteer at a bear sanctuary at Kuterevo Volunteers, Kuterevo, Croatia

July 2021 - August 2021

Help restore a bear sanctuary in Croatia. Development of new spaces for bears and volunteers. Animation of bear tours.

Festival Volunteer at Les Vieilles Charrues, Carhaix-Plouguer

July 2019 - August 2019

Helping organize the Vieilles charrues festival, one of the biggest French music festivals. Help with the catering, installation and dismantling of structures as well as the sale of merchandising goods.